rightster.com 2018-09-01

# Privacy Policy | Brave Bison

## Privacy & Cookie Policy

### Introduction

Brave Bison Limited, Brave Bison Group plc and each of their subsidiaries (collectively referred to as Brave Bison, "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This privacy notice will inform you as to how we use any of your personal data we might collect: (i) when we provide you with products or services; (ii) when you visit our websites or applications (regardless of where you visit it from); or (iii) in the course of conducting our day to day business.

  1. ### Information we may collect from you

#### Purpose of this privacy notice

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how Brave Bison collects and processes your personal data when providing services to you, through your visiting of our websites or applications, or otherwise in the course of conducting its day to day business. 

Our websites, applications and services are not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

#### Controller

Brave Bison is the controller and responsible for your personal data.

Brave Bison is made up of different legal entities. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of the Brave Bison Group so when we mention "Brave Bison", "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company in the Brave Bison Group responsible for processing your data. Brave Bison Limited is the controller and responsible for this website and other websites and applications incorporating this Privacy and Cookie Policy. 

We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the DPO using the details set out below.

#### Contact details

Our full details are:

Full name of legal entity: Brave Bison Limited

Name and Title of DPO: Alex Davids, Head of Legal and Business AffairsEmail address: [privacy@bravebison.io](mailto:privacy@bravebison.io)  
  
You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance. 

####   
Changes to the privacy notice and your duty to inform us of changes

This version was last updated on 12 April 2018.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

####   
Third-party links

Brave Bison’s websites and applications may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our websites or applications, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.
  2. ### The data we collect about you

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

    * Identity Data includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.
    * Contact Data includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
    * Financial Data includes bank account and payment card details.
    * Transaction Data includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.
    * Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access our websites or applications.
    * Profile Data includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
    * Usage Data includes information about how you use our websites, applications, products and services.
    * Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.
We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

We do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

#### If you fail to provide personal data

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.   

  3. ### How is your personal data collected?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through
    * Direct interactions. You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
    * request our products or services;
    * enter into discussions or correspondence with us in relation to our services;
    * enter into a contract with us;
    * create accounts on our websites or applications;
    * subscribe to our services or publications;
    * request marketing to be sent to you;
    * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
    * give us some feedback.
    * **Automated technologies or interactions**. As you interact with our websites or applications, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We would collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies. Please see our cookie policy at section under section 10 below for further details.
    * **Third parties or publicly available sources**. We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources as set out below:
    * Technical Data from analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU; and
    * Identity and Contact Data from publicly available sources such as Companies House and the Electoral Register based inside the EU.
  4. ### How we use your personal data

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:
    * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
    * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
    * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
Please see the Glossary under section 11 for descriptions of the types of lawful basis that we will rely on to process your personal data.

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.  

#### Purposes for which we will use your personal data

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

Purpose/Activity | Type of data |   
Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new client | (a) Identity   
(b) Contact | Performance of a contract with you  
To process and deliver services to you including (without limit):  
(a) Managing payments, fees and charges  
(b) Administering your account with us | (a) Identity   
(b) Contact   
(c) Financial   
(d) Transaction   
(e) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you   
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us)  
To manage our relationship with you  | (a) Identity   
(b) Contact   
(c) Profile   
(d) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you   
(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey | (a) Identity  **  
**(b) Contact   **  
**(c) Profile **   
** (d) Usage **   
** (e) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you   
(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
To administer and protect our business, websites and applications (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)  | (a) Identity  
(b) Contact  
(c) Technical | (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)  
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
To deliver relevant content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you  | (a) Identity   
(b) Contact   
(c) Profile   
(d) Usage   
(e) Marketing and Communications   
(f) Technical **   
** | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To use data analytics to improve our websites, applications, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | (a) Technical   
(b) Usage | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | (a) Identity   
(b) Contact   
(c) Technical   
(d) Usage   
(e) Profile | 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
#### Promotional offers from us 

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or used our services and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

#### Third-party marketing 

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside the Brave Bison group of companies for marketing purposes.   

####   
Opting out 

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us at any time.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of our provision of services.

#### Change of purpose

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us. 

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

  5. ### Disclosures of your personal data

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.
    * Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary under section 11.
    * External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary under section 11.
    * Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.
We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
  6. ### International transfers

We share your personal data within the Brave Bison Group. This will involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ).

Some of our external third parties are based outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

    * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.
    * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.
    * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

  7. ### Data security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. 

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

  8. ### Data retention

#### How long will you use my personal data for?

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. 

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available in our retention policy which you can request from us by contacting us.In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see section 9 below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

  9. ### Your legal rights

You have the right to:

 **Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

 **Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

 **Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. 

 **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

 **Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it. 

 **Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you. 

 **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.  

#### No fee usually required

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

#### What we may need from you

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

#### Time limit to respond

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 
  10. ### Cookies

Our websites and applications use cookies to distinguish you from other users. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our websites or applications and also allows us to improve our services. By continuing to browse, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is downloaded to your computer's hard drive.

We use strictly necessary cookies. These are cookies that are required for the operation of our websites and applications. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our websites or applications or use or make use of e-billing services. 

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our websites or applications.

We may revise and update this Cookies Policy at any time. Please periodically review the Cookies Policy, as your continued use of our sites indicates your agreement with any changes that we make.

  11. ### Glossary

#### LAWFUL BASIS

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.

 **Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.

 **Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation** means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.

#### THIRD PARTIES

#### Internal Third Parties

Other companies in the Brave Bison Group who are based in UK and Singapore.

#### External Third Parties

    * Service providers acting as processors based in UK, Republic of Ireland, Singapore and USA who provide IT and system administration services and online media services.
    * Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in UK, Singapore and USA who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
    * HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.

_12 April 2018_
